Disk Benchmark 


The measurements reveal the difference between the two platforms. AWS instance shows better performance than the Openstack VM, which shows that it uses an SSD. On the other hand, Openstack uses HDD which is slower than SSD. 


The measurements do not have a large difference when we compare Openstack and EC2 for the sequential operation by using the dd tool. 
However, there is a huge difference in the measurements of the performance of Openstack and EC2 for the random operation using the fio tool.
The reason behind the differences is the use of different storage solutions. It is clearly visible that Openstack shows much slower performance than EC2 because it uses HDD and EC2 has a better performance because it uses SSD.


CPU Benchmark (linpack.sh)


The linpack shell script compiles the linpack.c using the gcc compiler. After compilation the OS is checked and according to the check result the linpack is executed as .exe or linux executable. The code in linpack.c runs a while loop (called outer loop run (OLR)). Gaussian elimination method is used to solve the matrix which is present in the body of the loop and the equations are solved using the factors calculated by gaussian elimination. A total number of (2*n^3 / 3) + 2*n^2 operations are required in the two functions. This is repeated in the same OLR again. So, it is calculated twice and the number of ops doubles as well. The first OLR does all this once, ongoing from the second OLR it is calculated two times. If an OLR run is executed less than 10 seconds,  the other OLR is  being started again. If the OLR requires more than 10 seconds, the outer while loop stops.


The Linpack Benchmark measures a computer's floating-point rate of execution by using linear equation solutions . The computational power of the system can be calculated by using it.
It is not expected to para-virtualization has an affect on the results while the VMs has dedicated access to the host's resources, because these functions has just non-preferential directions.
Since these tasks involve only unprivileged instructions and are basically all executed on the CPU, we would not expect para-virtualization to affect the benchmark results as long as the virtualized machine has dedicated access to the host's resources.


The LINPACK measurements are consistent with our expectations. The Openstack instance gets lesser KFLOPS  than that we get on the AWS EC2 instance. It happens because only one virtualized CPU core is being used by the EC2 instance as we used t2.micro. On the other hand, Openstack virtual machine has the dual core architecture.



MEMORY BENCHMARK (memsweep.sh)


The shell script memsweep.sh compiles and runs the C file memsweep.c , taking into  consideration the target platform. The algorithm mentioned in memsweep.c creates a buffer and alters it frequently.
Virtual Machine has to be redirected by the host system since it cannot access the memory directly and due to overhead in the above process we observe a lower performance in the virtualized systems.


The benchmark on AWS EC2 shows better results than on OpenStack. This is consistent with our expectations, since the OpenStack has the component "cinder" which provides block level (traditional disk) storage to VMs on the other hand AWS offers Amazon EBS which provides the consistent performance and low latency for handling the processing loads.

							
						 					
				
			
		
